WENDY HUANG

I WANT TO BUILD TOOLS FOR HUMANS

melonho327@gmail.com https://github.com/melonHuang (86) 18588640327

Profile

I'm a Senior Front-End Engineer with 4 years working experience. Crafting interesting and useful tools is my jam. In the recent past, I have given talks at development conferences, started several open source projects, and actively participated in the translation of technical books.

Test

title

Work Experience

Qihoo 360 Technology Co. Ltd

Senior Front-End Developer - Annual Excellent Employee of department

Shengxiang - an online presentation editor

2016-2017

- 1. Led a team of four Front-End developers, enforced coding standards, kept the group engaged and passionate.
- 2. Designed predictable, scalable architecture with the help of Vue&Vuex (React&Redux alike Javascript libraries).
- Automated workflow for development, testing, and production environment with the help of Gulp, Webpack, PostCSS, etc.
- 4. Designed database tables and implemented Back-End logics and APIs using ThinkJS (a Back-End MVC Framework).
- 5. Designed innovative features and transformed them into coordinated ART and IT deliverables.

Baomitu - an interactive mobile storytelling platform

2015-2016

Built componentized architecture by designing Nova.js (a web component framework like Polymer).

Mobile Guard 2014-2015

- r. Responsible for all Front-End requirements of Mobile Guard Department, including official websites, mobile-side pages for special events and cross-device webviews.
- 2. Made quick response and decisions to several independent and concurrent requirements every day, while making effective plans and guaranteeing high quality deliverables.
- 3. Delivered high performance and compatible cross-device web pages.
- 4. Designed NovaUI (an open source mobile-side component gallery) to share common mobile-side components with the other engineers.

CRM System 2013-2014

- r. Wrote consistent, concise, and well documented codes to build pages full of form manipulations and chart presentations.
- 2. Abstracted and designed common plugins for reusability.

Open Source Projects

Nova.js

Javascript Library - Creator

2015 - 2016

A production-ready Web Component Framework, only 12KB after gziped, providing an easy way to define custom element with data binding, CSS Scoping, etc.

NovaUI

Javascript Library - Creator & Main Contributor

2013 - 2016

A mobile side component gallery with high animation performance, flexible APIs and clear documents.

AnimationGenerator

Chrome Extension - Creator

2014

A Chrome Devtools extension which can help generate animation codes for web pages quickly.

Speech

CSSConf - High Performance Animation

Shanghai, China

2015

Other Talks

https://melonhuang.github.io/sharing/

Publication

The Mobile Handbook

Translated Chapters 3 - 4 from English to Madarine

2015

Education

Sun Yat-sen University Software Engineering BSc

2009-2013

Skills

Modern Web Stack

- 1. HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, DOM scripting
- 2. Mobile-Side development, responsive web design
- 3. Node.js and MVC Back-End Framework
- 4. Network knowleges including HTTP protol, TCP handshakes, etc
- 5. Fullstack, able to design database tables, implement Back-End logics and design UI
- 6. Good documenting habit

Rich Experience in

- Performance
 Optimization
- 2. Large-scale web applications, designing scalable architecture and workflow
- 3. Javascript Application Framework - Vue.js
- 4. Cross-browser and cross-device development, handling compatibility issues

Tools & Libraries

- npm, gulp, webpack, postCSS, babel, thinkjs, eslint, mocha.js, chai.js, etc
- 2. vim, git/svn, chrome devtools, photoshop, zsh,
- 3. Vue.js, Polymer, jQuery, Zepto, etc